=As Promised=
(Adapted from "The Villain's Guide to Love",
a story on Zhihu Yanyan)
=Episode 11=
If you insist on this course,
then I'll...
Father, don't act rashly!
His Highness cares
deeply about the realm.
He would never lose
himself in matters of love.
He only said those things
because he was drunk.
Once sober, he'll know what's at stake.
You've played this part for so long.
Do you really think you're
Zhao Boqing's trusted confidant?
Princess Yun Fang
is clearly devoted to you.
Why haven't you asked for her hand?
The Princess and I...
Have you also let yourself
be blinded by love?
How foolish!
I've paid with my own lifespan
to disrupt the stars,
gain Zhao Boqing's trust,
and force He Xiaoyuan
to become involved
with the Crown Prince.
Who do you think I did all this for?
Father...
Father.
Zhao Boqing and He Xiaoyuan
are the true fated pair.
How could I not fear
them growing closer?
This thirty-fourth lifetime
is our last chance.
If anything goes wrong this time,
we'll never have
another chance to succeed.
Don't forget,
you and I
are descendants
of the former royal family.
Everything I've done
has been to pave
a clear path
for you to reach the very top.
I'm sorry.
I was wrong.
I placed you
by Zhao Boqing's side all these years
because he
is destined to rule.
He is bound to control
the political factions
and wield authority
over matters of state.
Only by remaining deeply embedded
and earning his complete trust,
only then can you one day
seamlessly take over everything he has.
I
understand.
If you
truly understand all I've done for you,
then become Princess Yun Fang's
Prince Consort without delay.
Only if Zhao Boqing
loses He Xiaoyuan,
his fated companion star,
will he be unable
to fully secure the throne.
Then you, as Prince Consort,
can purge the court
of corrupt influences
and overthrow the Crown Prince,
then take control of Great Yue.
Yes.
I
will never let
your efforts go to waste.
(Father and son.)
(Descendants
of the former royal family.)
(No wonder.)
(Imperial Preceptor,)
(all this time, you and Fu Yang
have spared no effort to assist me,)
(and cared more about
my quest for the realm than I did.)
(So He Xiaoyuan and I
are the ones destined for each other.)
(So you were behind the chaos
of all thirty-three lifetimes.)
(So having your son Fu Yang
eventually ascend the throne)
(was your ultimate goal all along.)
(So this thirty-fourth lifetime)
(was never my last chance.)
(Qingyan Palace)
(It was yours.)
Boqing.
Fu Yang asked Mother for my hand today.
Mother has agreed.
From now on,
your Study Companion is mine.
Boqing,
why are you always picking on Fu Yang?
Fu Yang,
that day,
you gave me a gold hairpin as a token.
So this jade pendant
is my gift in return.
From now on,
you may visit
the Princess's Residence often.
Come see me often.
Thank you
for your affection, Your Highness.
Yun Fang,
you should head back first.
Fu Yang and I still have
important matters to discuss.
All right.
Remember to come see me.
Yun Fang truly loves you.
After deceiving her like this,
do you really feel no remorse at all?
What do you mean, Your Highness?
Yes. I will never let
Father's efforts go to waste.
Only if Zhao Boqing loses
He Xiaoyuan, his fated companion star,
will he be unable
to fully secure the throne.
Then you, as Prince Consort,
can purge the court of corrupt influences
and overthrow the Crown Prince,
then take control of Great Yue.
You plotted against me.
Fu Yang,
who has really
been plotting against whom?
You and your father have kept
your relationship
and identities deeply hidden.
I've schemed and struggled
through thirty-three lifetimes.
I never imagined
my greatest enemy
was right beside me.
As expected.
Someone as clear-headed
and resilient as Your Highness
would never get drunk for no reason.
I've lost.
Your Highness,
I failed in my duty.
The Imperial Preceptor
has fled the Observatory.
Where did he go?
Tell me.
Your Highness,
what you should be
more concerned about right now
is He Xiaoyuan's safety.
Now that my father has fled,
his next move
will surely be to destroy
your path to the throne.
Do you think
he'll spare your companion star?
Xiaoyuan!
Are you all right?
(One hour earlier)
Drink slowly.
Zhao Junyao
is a kind but weak Crown Prince,
unfit to rule.
It's only a matter
of time before the realm falls.
But
he is innocent too.
In this lifetime,
I won't kill him.
Such defiance of fate.
Xiaoyuan,
you...
What exactly
have you gotten yourself into?
Xiaoyuan,
isn't Daniu an escort?
What does he really do?
Let me explain.
The Seventh Prince has ordered
everyone but He Xiaoyuan
to be killed.
Who are you?
What are you doing?
- Who are you?
- What are you doing?
Xiaoyuan!
What are you doing?
Let them go!
- Let them go!
- Let go of me!
Help!
Other than you, who still has value,
no one
can be allowed to threaten
His Highness's path to the throne.
That includes
your parents and family.
Burn this place down.
They're gone.
Father...
Mother...
And my sister...
They're all gone.
Why?
Xiaoyuan.
Fu Yang said
nothing can jeopardize
your path to the throne.
So...
So
my family, who accidentally
learned your secret,
had to die.
But I don't believe him.
That's why I'm waiting here for you
to tell me the truth yourself.
Xiaoyuan,
believe me.
I never gave such an order.
Fu Yang has betrayed me.
It's dangerous here now.
Let me take you back first.
I promise I'll give you an explanation.
Let's go.
Whether you did it or not,
I'm not going with you.
Why?
Just come with me first.
Zhao Boqing!
My father, mother,
and sister are already dead.
What difference
would an explanation make now?
I...
It's my fault.
I shouldn't have gotten close to you,
nor should I have become
involved in your grand ambitions.
All I ever wanted
was for them to get
the treatment they needed
and live out their lives in peace.
Why, in the end,
did I still bring this upon them?
Xiaoyuan.
It's all my fault.
Xiaoyuan, don't be afraid.
I'm here.
What's going on?
Boqing,
are you really involved in this?
Why is the Crown Prince here?
Xiaoyuan sent me a message
by carrier pigeon
telling me where she was.
(Written by He Xiaoyuan in tears)
(What's going on?)
Xiaoyuan.
Give these people a proper burial.
Yes.
♪My longing has nowhere to rest♪
♪Through the storm, I drift and sway♪
♪You are the prayer I hold in my palm♪
♪In one frozen moment,
my tears come into focus♪
♪My heart has long known♪
♪We made a promise long ago♪
♪To stay together until the end of time♪
♪You are the fate I cannot escape♪
♪How much must I let go♪
♪For one moment♪
♪To hold each other close♪
♪Would that be enough?♪